A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 2007-2013
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Finance, 2007-2013
The Library of Virginia
51173, 53531
3.3 cu.ft. (8 boxes)
Virginia. Office of the Secretary of Finance
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The folders must be reviewed before being served (Series I). Privacy protected information is considered closed for 75 years after date of record creation per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: state income tax returns.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 30 January 2014 by the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Finance, 1111 East Broad Street, 3rd Floor, Richmond, Virginia, 23219 [Acc. 51173].
Transferred on 14 January 2022 by the Office of the Governor, Richmond, Virginia, 23219 [Acc. 53531].
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties, compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
Since the establishment of a secretarial system in 1972, there have been several reorganizations of that system. The financial management function of the state has shifted from under the direction of the Secretary of Finance to the Secretary of Administration; then to Secretary of Administration and Finance and currently back to the Secretary of Finance, through various reorganizations of state government from 1970s to the present. The function of the secretary is to provide sound fiscal management and recommend to the Governor a comprehensive budget for those agencies under his jurisdiction. The secretary's responsibilities are: to monitor programs, services and performance of subordinate state agencies to develop state policies programs for long-range planning and policy formulation; and approve solicitation or acceptance of any donations, gifts or grants; to hold agency heads accountable for their agency's administrative, fiscal and program performance. All secretaries are appointed by the governor and serve at his will.
Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014) reappointed Richard "Ric" D. Brown to serve as Secretary of Finance. Richard Brown was appointed as Secretary of Finance by Governor Timothy Kaine in 2008 and continued to serve until 2018.
Scope and Content
Records, 2007-2013, of Secretary of Finance Richard "Ric" D. Brown during the administrations of Governor Timothy M. Kaine and Governor Robert F. McDonnell. The collection is housed in eight boxes and includes budget reports, charts, correspondence, drafts of House Bills, presentations, press releases, reports, and spreadsheets. The collection is arranged into two series: Series I: Constituent Correspondence and Series II: Correspondence and Subject Files (Transportation).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Constituent Correspondence, 2010-2013 [Accession 51173]
Series II: Correspondence and Subject files (Transportation), 2007-2013 [Accession 53531]
Contents List
- Series I: Constituent Correspondence [Accession 51173], 2010-2013, Extent: 1.05 cu. ft. (3 boxes). (Box 1-3)
  Series I: Constituent correspondence, 2010-2013, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance, Richard D. Brown, during the administration of Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014). Topics include constituent tax issues, retirement contributions, Medicaid, and budgetary requests from state agencies and local governments in Virginia. Also included are VIP letter tracking sheets detailing the topic of the letter and whether a response was sent.
  - 2010 January-March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 2010 April-May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 2010 June-August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2010 September-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 2011 January-July (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2011 August (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 2011 August (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 2011 September (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 2011 October (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 2011 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 2011 November-December (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 2012 January (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2012 February-March (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 2012 April (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 2012 May-August (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 2012 August-December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Series II: Correspondence and Subject files (Transportation) [Accession 53531], 2007-2013, Extent: 2.25 cu. ft. (5 boxes). (Box 1-)
  Series II: Correspondence and Subject files (Transportation), 2007-2013, created and maintained by Secretary of Finance, Richard D. Brown, during the administrations of Governor Timothy M. Kaine (2006-2010) and Governor Robert F. McDonnell (2010-2014). Includes budget reports, charts, correspondence, drafts of House Bills, presentations, press releases, reports, and spreadsheets relating to transportation, funding for transportation, and the NVTA (Northern Virginia Transportation Authority). Other topics include the closure of rest stops on I-95 (2009), Governor's budgets, retail sales and gas taxes, and budget amendments.
  - Comments on Transportation Finance, 2010 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2012 December-2013 January (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2013 January (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 2013 January-February (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2013 February (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2013 February-March (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2013 March (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2013 March-April (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2013 April-June (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2013 November-2017 August (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - House Whip count, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Reappropriations, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Funding Legislative Proposals, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
  - Secretary of Transportation, Funding Legislative Proposals, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Tax and Transportation Alternatives, 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Transportation, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Transportation, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Transportation Bill (HB 3202), 2007 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Va. Dept of Taxation, Joint Subcommittee to Study Tax Preferences, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 4)